Everything he touches turns into excitement!
Goldfinger is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by Guy Hamilton.
Special agent 007 comes face to face with one of the most notorious villains of all time, and now he must outwit and outgun the
powerful tycoon to prevent him from cashing in on a devious scheme to raid Fort Knox -- and obliterate the world's economy.
James Bond, played by Sean Connery.
Auric Goldfinger, played by Gert Fröbe.
Pussy Galore, played by Honor Blackman.
Oddjob, played by Harold Sakata.
Jill Masterson, played by Shirley Eaton.
Tilly Masterson, played by Tania Mallet.
Goldfinger is a 1964 spy film and the third instalment in the James Bond series produced by
Eon Productions, starring Sean Connery as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
It is based on the 1959 novel by Ian Fleming.
The film also stars Honor Blackman, Gert Fröbe and Shirley Eaton.
Goldfinger was produced by Albert R.
Broccoli and Harry Saltzman.
The film was the first of four Bond films directed by Guy Hamilton.
The plot has Bond investigating the gold magnate Auric Goldfinger, who plans to
irradiate the United States Bullion Depository at Fort Knox with a dirty bomb.
Goldfinger was the first Bond film to take over $100 million, with a
budget equal to that of the two preceding films combined.
Principal photography took place from January to July 1964 in the
United Kingdom, Switzerland and the United States.
Goldfinger was heralded as the film in the franchise
where James Bond "comes into focus".
Many elements introduced in it appeared in many of the later Bond films, such as the extensive use of technology and gadgets by Bond, an
extensive pre-credits sequence that stood largely alone from the main plot, multiple foreign locales and tongue-in-cheek humour.
The film's release led to a number of promotional licensed tie-in items, including a toy Aston Martin DB5 car from Corgi
Toys, which became the biggest-selling toy of 1964, and an image of the gold-painted Eaton on the cover of Life.
Goldfinger was the first Bond film to win an Academy Award (for Best Sound
Editing) and opened to largely favourable critical reception.
The film was a financial success, recouping its budget in two
weeks and grossing over $120 million worldwide.
In 1999, it was ranked 70th on the BFI Top 100 British films list.
Goldfinger was followed by Thunderball in 1965.
The film explores themes of airplane, based on novel or book,
england, secret intelligence service, golf.
The tone is intense.